Hey, man, stop!
Mister, we want your money.
Hurry
Hurry up!
Do it now!
No!
A TOUCH OF SIN
Black Gold Mountain
What is the path to the Black Gold Mountain?
You're on it.
- Rodovia 307? - Keep going that way.
Dahai.
Whose bike is that out there?
- I do not know. - Do not know!
Sit down, Dahai.
It's been standing there for two days. No idea whose it is.
If nobody claims her, I'll sell it.
So if the Audi A6 the village chief was parked ...
outside his house, would you sell that, too?
What do you think?
That A6 belongs to everyone here in the village.
He sold the state the coal mine ...
for the money to buy that fancy car.
So that's why I found the car so familiar.
Those shiny new wheels are actually mine.
You caught the spirit.
Dahai. It's a shame you were not born ...
for example, before the war.
Surely you would have made the rank of General.
We'll see what happens when I make the complaint to Beijing.
The boss and the new boss, Jiao will be sent to jail.
Before even reaching Tainan ...
the boss's men will bribe you.
Why do you think I studied law?
Boss sold a collective property,  which he could not do.
The bastard accepted bribes.
Surely he'll get 20 years.
As for the boss, Jiao Shengli, he's also involved in that, is he not?
He will be charged with theft ...
and covering up accidents in the mine.
All this serves to close the mine.
Believe you me. Believe it.
If the coal mine had been  yours ...
you also would have acted just like him. Just like him.
Sure.
Jiao's Maserati is parked in the courtyard.
He never drives it.
If you sell it, you can buy a drink for everyone.
I don't want his damnar.
Sanming.
- Bought a train ticket? - Yes, I bought one.
- For what? - See my wife on the New Year.
How romantic!
The police are here.
Police. Come on, stop eating. Stop eating.
Inspectors.
All here are migrant workers?
Yes.
- What's the problem? - A crime in Shibawan.
The migrants need to be interrogated.
Everyone out there.
Alright.
Quickly.
Chief. Village chief ...
when you sold the coal mine you promised ...
profit sharing. So where's our part?
I said that in a private conversation.
I don't have time for this right now.
Right. So explain this to the disciplinary committee.
You picked the wrong time to get into a fight.
Could end up getting killed.
You do not want to discuss it?
You talk too much.
Very well. These are from Chongqing.
Stay there. Next.
He's running.
Fucking animal!
What's happening, Dahai?
I am writing to the disciplinary committee ...
to file a complaint against the boss and Jiao Shengli.
Girl. A registered letter.
Where to?
Beijing. Zhongnanhal. The committee.
I need the full address.
Zhongnanhai, Beijing.
That's not enough. I need the whole address.
What? Everyone knows Zhongnanhai.
But it's not enough.
Girl, are you on the boss's side?
Is he paying you off?
Or are you fucking Jiao? Did he buy you a car?
Are you crazy? Go away!
You two must be together in this.
Out.
There is no justice! There is no justice!
There is no justice!
Hurry!
All aboard! We are starting!
Let's go!
Dahai!
Dahai! Come on!
Dahai! Come on! Come on!
What  is this about?
It's a gift from boss Jiao. A bag of flour per person.
Come up here, come on.
Jiao has a new private jet.
He's flying in from Hong Kong.
We are the welcoming party.
Everyone will receive a bag of flour.
A plane?
To live on this earth is not enough for him?
Dahai, say, were you at the coal mine when they started shooting?
I was.
Who was the guy who ran?
A hauler from the coal field. From Sichuan.
Why did he run?
Weren't the murders in Shibawan?
He is an escaped prisoner.
Killed someone in his hometown.
He's wanted there.
He thought he would be arrested.
The guy panicked and fled.
And did they get him?
Of course they did.
- What happened in Shibawan? - Have not you heard?
Someone killed three guys yesterday.
Three died in Shibawan.
- Says who? - I do not know.
Earlier today, armed police were
em Shibawan.
Right. How tragic, right?
Accountant Liu. Your accounts are up to date?
Listen. When the boss Jiao bought the coal mine ...
he said 40% of the profits would go to the village.
How much of the last 14 years of earnings he owes?
Listen. In 2001 ...
village council signed the sale of the coal mine.
Who asked you to sell?
Was the contract discussed?
We had to keep our word.
But Jiao is so rich that he even bought a plane.
That's not fair.
He works hard.
How much did you get in bribes?.
- How much? Tell me, how much? - Hey, come on, please.
How much did you take in bribes?
Open the door.
People like you, are more miserable ...
and diabolical than the village boss and Jiao.
Just listen ... They ...
Do not talk to me.
Repeat all.
Welcome. Welcome! Warm greetings!
Great.
The plane's coming.
Welcome. Welcome! Warm greetings!
Mr. Jiao, you have reached a new level.
Let's move forward together.
Congratulations, lady. Children,  the flowers.
Welcome. Welcome! Warm greetings!
Mr. Jiao, look here.
Closer. This.
- Say something, sir. - Later.
Let's go.
How are you, Aunt?
Thanks for coming. Wow, it's been awhile!.
Shengli!
Dahai.
- Shengli. Congratulations! - Thanks, Dahai.
You're a hard man to reach.
I have a topic you'd like to discuss with you.
I need a favor.
Whatever you need, just ask.
Sponsor my trip to Beijing.
To bring charges against you and the village chief.
I know. Come talk to me later.
No, here in front of everybody.
Can you not discuss the economy of the village?
What are you are looking at?!
Xiao Bai, you play golf?
I'm here to apologize on behalf of Shengli group.
Case closed.
Where's your mother?
Who are you?
Do not you remember me?
I'm your uncle, from Black Gold Mountain.
Mama went out to look for food. She'll be back soon.
"Animal".
And where is your father?
Out hunting ... "animals".
- On which mountain? - Jiaokou.
Dahai.
But what ...
What are you doing here?
I'm going to stay in the city for a couple days.
Feel free, then.
Ganggang, eat first, then do the school work.
Okay, mother.
But what ...
They told me...
Years ago I introduced you to a woman Wangchun.
You were a beautiful couple.
But you ... Why did you not want to go out with her?
You never thought of yourself.
And now you are making accusations.
Even if you keep right on talking, you will get old.
I am old. I do not care.
Do not be silly. You are in middle age.
The kids are home.
I miss you.
You're still immature.
I told you when we were in school.
There's more to life than getting rich.
You want to be worse than Jiao Shengli?
What? How can you compare me to him?
If not him, then who?
You and he were classmates.
Look at what he has become.
Compared with us here.
You have your house in Wujinshan.
But my husband and I have a house that is ours.
Enough complaining.
If you have time and money, open a restaurant or a store.
To make money and get married. Your life belongs to you.
Stop worrying about what others do.
My dear, wait and see.
You bet I'll be worse than the village head or Jiao.
Sr. Golf?
- What did you call me? - Mr. Golf.
That's what they're calling you. Did you not know?
Mr. Golf.
Eu...
Lin Chong...
I grabbed my sword in anger ...
and beheaded two henchmen Gao Giu.
Fortunately for me, the official Chai ...
gave me a document that prevents me ...
from going to Mount Liang.
Dahai.
Good day.
Dahai, good day
I want to talk to your husband.
Feel free.
Write.
Write what?
You know how much the village chief pocketed.
Make a confession.
You're being ridiculous.
What are you doing? This is dangerous.
Write.
Write it!
Shoot!
Come on, shoot!
You are too cowardly to kill me!
Dahai!
Hello? Village boss.
It Liuliu. I just got here.
What do you want me to do?
Do not worry. I'll do it this afternoon.
Mr. Golf.
- Where's the boss? - He's in the temple.
What did you call me?
Mr. Golf. Isn't that your foreign name?
Asshole.
What did you say?
- Dahai! - What is it?
- Where are you going?
Are you going hunting?
Yes. Hunting animals.
Dahai. Do not do anything stupid.
Calm down.
Let's sit down and talk.
And solve this issue.
Listen, Dahai, do not be impulsive.
Let sit ...
Idiot.
Dahai?
How can we take care of it? Let's just talk.
Hey mister. Mister, you got a light?
No.
Motorcycle taxi! Motorcycle taxi!
- Hey man, where are you going? - Take the expressway.
Towards Chongging or Wushan?
Wushan.
Let's go.
Our dear Ms. Zhou worked hard to raise their children.
And now,as she turns 70, we wish her ...
happiness, good health and long life.
And now, let's welcome the second son and his family.
And his good wishes.
All her children are here!
The younger son has returned!
You're back ...
Brother ...
Why are you running away?
Come here. Come here.
Mother
Do not cry.
How did you come?
I came by boat.
And before that?
I received the money you sent. 130,000 yuan.
That's right.
The latest shipment was from Shanxi.
I earned it in Wuhan and sent it from Shanxi.
I do not want your money.
Your brothers are coming.
Mom's birthday was on November 7th.
But we both had to work all day.
We could not go home.
Our relatives were also unable to go home.
And now that it's New Year's and many people ...
go home, we decided to celebrate today.
I'll be honest with you.
To commemorate 70 years of the mother, we received gifts ...
Cash totaling 10,270 yuan.
12 tables of guests
To buy meat, vegetables, wine and cigarettes the total cost ...
was 6,477 yuan and 33 cents.
I hired a host for 800 yuan.
Taking into account all expenses ...
the total expenditure was 7,485 yuan and 42 cents.
That was the total cost.
Which leaves us with two thousand 784 yuan and 58 cents.
This money, in my opinion, should be divided between ...
the three of us and Mom. One fourth for everyone.
I already divided it for us. Into four equal parts.
- Okay. Second brother? - Okay. Right.
I do not need the money. Give my part to mother.
I brought 10 packs of cigarettes. Good brand.
Nine are missing. So there are 3 for each.
As elder brother I have to be impartial.
Soon.
If you want to give your part to Mom, give it to her yourself.
People usually worship the gods in the morning.
I am worshipping ghosts.
The gods are for blaming.
If you have any sorrows, tell the heavens about them.
Quinqin is in Dongguan? She returned to you?
She was sent to Zhongshan.
She will not return.
The tested HIV positive.
She has AIDS? Didn't she work in the factory?
Yes.
It's impossible to make a decent living.
Lili has a hairdressing salon in Zhongshan ...
Quinqin went to work for her.
She provided "special services" there. That's how she got AIDS.
Blonde. You slept with her once.
You better get a check-up.
Do not talk nonsense!
A quick check-up can't hurt. I wish you good luck.
What your wife doing up in Tianjin ...
while you're stuck here? You should keep an eye on her.
Maybe you have HIV.
Come on, man!
You should keep your mouth shut.
Want to die?
Son of a bitch. We'll sort it out here and now.
Going to fight?
It's only 78 minutes until the New Yearr.
Think you can take me?
- Should we light some fireworks? - Cool!
Look!
Tickets to Guangzhou, 240 yuan.
Wuhan! Anyone for Wuhan?
Want a ticket?
- Do have any for Nanning? - Yes, how many do you want?
For where else?
Yichang.
One to Guangzhou, Nanning and Yichang.
Wait for me at the bridge, pick up the tickets there.
- Don't take long. - Wait for me.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the Chonqqing railway station ... reminds everyone ...
that during the holiday season ...
it is strictly prohibited carrying combustible materials ...
Are you going to Guangzhou
Yichang...
or Nanning?
You went through my things?
I'm not sure. I would go to Burma.
You can't stay here in the village?
It is boring.
What is boring?
Shooting is not boring.
And what would you do in Burma?
I need to buy a new gun.
You should buy a cellphone. So I could call you.
No way, it's very dangerous.
Can I help you?
I'm just looking.
Take your time.
- Where is the bathroom? - Right there.
Can you watch my backpack? I'll be right back.
Okay. I look after it.
BANK OF CHONGQING
- Go ahead and start the car. - Be careful.
You can leave.
Xiaoyan! Where are you going?
I'm taking him for a vaccination. It's time for the injection.
But how cute! Is he scared?
No.
- And the rest? - As usual.
Let's have tea sometime.
Sure.
Hey, driver, here.
Hey, stop!
I can't, only on the next rest stop.
Here!
- Did you take transit? - A delay in Tianmen.
When did you get here?
I just got in.
You're frowning.
Should we go to to the station?
I rented a car. The driver is waiting.
Hello? Wang? It's me.
Car rented by Xiaoyu.
You can come now. Right.
You told her?
I started to.
What did you say?
I left it implicit.
You're stalling again.
She must have understood.
Come with me to Guangzhou.
I've been with you for many years. And what have I got?
I accepted things the way they were.
But I owe my parents an explanation.
I want a child.
Let's go together to Guangzhou.
Either you stay with your wife, and we get separated ...
or you leave her and live with me.
You have to choose.
Let's stay together.
So you go back to Guangzhou, and I give you 6 months.
We need to think it over before we make a decision.
Sir, there's a problem with your luggage.
Please, come this way.
Open your luggage.
You can not take that on the train.
It's a fruit knife.
It is not allowed.
Why not?
It's the law.
And if I want to eat an apple?
Eat with the skin.
Give it to me, then. I'll take it.
You can not go.
I'm not going.
Or enter the station.
Stay with the knife.
Your ID?
I'll leave first. Call me when you get there.
Here, you can go.
This is the final call for the 9:34 train ...
from Yichang to Guangzhou.
Dear citizens of Yuanshan, come take a look.
Come and see. Come and see.
See the sacred snakes. See their beauty.
Marriage is the destination.
The sacred snakes predict happiness and distress.
Come and see. Come and see.
See the sacred snakes. See their beauty.
SPA AND HOTEL
Good evening, sir. Overnight or sauna?
Are you Xiayou?
I am.
I am Zhang, Youllang's wife.
Why?!
Shameless bitch. I'll kill you!
Your mother gave birth to you just to seduce my husband?
Number 11, your turn.
Thank you.
- Thank you. - You're welcome.
You were in there a long time.
You should know how things are.
Around here, I don't have much to do to make money.
I'd rather stay here.
When will this airport will be ready?
They are working on the railroad first.
When this is over, most workers will leave.
I will, too.
Mother ..
I saw father in Yichang.
I don't want to know anything about him.
Amazing! How did this happen?
Yesterday at 8:38, the train from Beijing to Fuzhou ...
via Shuanguy and Wenzhou ...
crashed into a train that was stopped en route from Hengzhou to Fuzhou.
The collision made the first 4 cars plummet from the viaduct.
Two cars of another train also fell.
At the moment, the death toll comes to 35. 19 have been identified.
Among them are two foreigners. In total, 210 people were injured.
- Pay the fee. - What rate?
- To pass through, 10 yuan. - We work on the site.
Then you will understand.
When your trucks pass through our city, they leave holes.
As of today will have to pay a fee.
But I'm just an employee.
It makes no difference.
You work at the airport?
I'll pay if you give me a receipt.
A receipt?
Come here.
Give the receipt to him.
Stop or you'll kill him.
An animal commits suicide?
For those who think that humans ...
are the only advanced creatures on earth ...
Xiaoyu, your shift is over.
Did you know that animals commit suicide?
They don't know what they're talking about.
Better to live miserable than die happy.
The animals do not agree.
Good evening, gentlemen.
Sauna or spend the night?
Sauna, and then give us a room.
Sauna. Two patrons to the sauna.
Washing clothes?
Yes.
What is your number here?
I have no number.
Give me a massage.
Please go to the third floor. The masseuses are there.
I do not want a professional.
Give me a full body massage. I paid.
Sorry, sir, I'm the receptionist, I am not masseuse.
Receptionist? Then why are you up here?
Excuse me.
What are you implying?
Nothing.
Do not turn your back on me.
You will be well rewarded.
Fuck you!
Damn! Stop pretending! I'll have you.
I'm not a masseur.
Then why are you working in a sauna?
Out!
Damn! You only get with beautiful men, huh?
We have money to pay you.
I'm not a prostitute. Go home to your wives.
What do you want now?
- I'll have you. - No you will not.
I will.
- I have money. - Money can not buy everything.
I have money.
It is not good enough is it?
Not good enough?
My money is not good enough, is it? Bitch.
You're not a prostitute, are you? I know you'll do anything for money.
You're like all the others, doing it for money.
Bitch! Bitch! I have money!
My money is good.
Bitch!
Go fuck yourself!
My money is not good, is it? Bitch! My money is good, yes.
Bitch, you will learn a lesson.
You are not a prostitute? Is that so?
Bitch. You're a slut.
You are.. Take this to learn.
His ...
Bitch!
Hello, You have reached the police. What do you want?
I killed someone.
Hands off my mobile.
And where's the GPS?
If you want a GPS, buy a fucking BMW.
I'm going to see a friend in Dongguan. I do not know the way.
Call a motorcycle taxi. Then take a train.
A high speed train?
Which town in Dongguan?
Humen.
Humen?
Help me.
What should I do? The rule of the company is clear:
No chat during office hours.
Today's accident was your fault.
Agree or not?
The company will pay for medical treatment.
You will pay by the hour for his work.
It will take two weeks to get his hand healed.
During this period his salary goes to him.
You work for him.
Ladies and gentlemen, our next stop is Dongguan.
Hey, man. What's up?
Hi.
While he is on leave, he gets my salary.
If he is out 100 days, I go 100 days without pay.
What the hell! This means that you work for him.
So I left. Fortunately I had got paid a few days earlier.
So you have some money..
Come work here. Companies are hiring.
Basically they pay 1,200 yuan, plus room and board.
How much do people usually get?
Nearly 2,500 yuan.
Training?
A week without pay.
Anything in particular?
You could work as a waiter in Changping.
Waiter?
It's a nightclub. The owners are from Hong Kong and Taiwan.
The tips are good, but you would have to work all night.
It is near here?
No, it's in another town in Dongguan.
Hello, Mr. Lau
This guy is from my village. Please, take care of him.
Your buddy?
Yes, his name is Xiaohui.
Xiaohui, come in.
Call me if anything happens.
Nothing will happen.
- Take care of him. - I will.
When a guest arrives, do not call him "sir."
As of now he is the "distinguished guest".
You say, "Good evening, distinguished guest ...
welcome to the Golden Age. "
Now repeat what I say: Good evening, distinguished guest.
Good evening, distinguished guest, welcome to the Golden Age
Now in Cantonese.
In English.
Take the guest to room 214
What are you doing?
I didn't see anything.
What you did not see?
Nothing.
It's okay, I'm not naked.
- You're the newbie? - Yeah.
Your name?
Xiaohui.
From Hunan?
How did you know?
Easy. By your accent.
I am also from Hunan.
Help me out here.
I'm Lianrong.
It means "lotus seed".
Easy to remember.
Delightful.
Fate brought us together here.
Fate brings a lot of people together here.
Help me with the tie?
Sir ...
Hello? I'm in Dongguan.
A painting by Xu Beihong?
Buy. It's a great investment.
Okay, see you in Macau. Hanging up.
- Slacking off? - No.
And you? Are you slacking off?
The Wi-Fi is good in this room.
Do they have many guests?
I'll explain.
One shift arrives at one in the morning. The other  at three.
And another at five.
It's snowing in Shangi and Mongolia.
No way. It's 24 degrees here in Dongguan.
Shit!
The minister of the city bought almost 130 bags of Louis Vitton.
Why did he buy so much?
- It is actually a she. - A woman needs all that?
Like I said, she is a lady.
I'll post a comment.
What should I write?
Fuck that.
Fuck that!
The bags are worth more than 2 million yuan.
Anything else?
A mine exploded in Shanxi. Dozens killed.
Post a comment.
Post what?
Fuck that.
Fuck that!
What's your username?
Well my handle is Little Bird.
Is it little?
Hey now you've gone too far!
Stop.
Just a hand! You were embarrassed.
And what is your username?
Wow! I forgot!
They're not dead.
You keep fish?
I will release them tomorrow.
Are you Buddhist?
I am. In this kind of work ...
the Cantonese call us illegal traders.
So we need to do many good deeds to ...
be forgiven in our next life.
You got it ... Little Bird?
My handle is Fish Seeks Water.
I'm here..
Distinguished guest, welcome to the Golden Age
Welcome. The distinguished guests from room 7 have arrived.
Now for the 1st lesson of the series “Learn to speak Cantonese.”
When you find the ideal person ...
You'll know what to say in Cantonese.
When two people meet for the first time ...
if the boy is brave enough he will say "I like you".
In Dongguan, it is more common that...
the girls approach the boys ...
What?
I only know one phrase in Cantonese.
Tell me.
I really like you.
Let's leave Dongguan.
And where will you take me?
Anywhere works, as long as you come with me.
There is no real love in sex work.
Think you really know me?
I have a daughter.
That day you saw me on the train, I was going to see her in Guangzhou.
She lives there.
I have to get her.
- Where's yours? - The music room. And yours?
In the train room.
Come in.
I want a driver, not a nurse.
Would it not be better with a nurse? You need to consider your health.
That's enough. Go look for sick customers.
But ...
My health is excellent. You can go.
Please, wait.
- Your fruit, distinguished guest. - Let it there.
Distinguished guest, can I help you?
Take me to the conductor of the train
That's me.
Very well. Let's get going.
Where?
You do not know where we're going?
We can wherever you want to.
You kids today have no sense of direction.
Is that some recent innovation?
Come here.
Relax, buddy.
I have nowhere to go. I came here to join you.
Think about it. If you stay, do not fuck around, or I'll get scolded.
I know.
OASIS OF PROSPERITY
- Are you a newbie? - Yes I'm in training.
Hi. Welcome, I'm your supervisor.
Welcome to the Fortune 500. Work hard.
The best employees earn a trip to Taiwan ...
- To visit our headquarters. - Okay.
- Good luck. Where are you from? - Hunan.
- And you? - Taiwan.
Hi, Mom.
Did not send you money recently?
I'm in a new job. We get paid at the end of the month.
I really do not, I'm broke.
Why would I lie?
I'm coming off the bench now. I don't have any money.
I'm not wasting. I can not live with nothing.
I will not rob a bank.
I did not waste the money.
Did you really think you could escape? Chang Ling wants to see him.
- Hu Yunyun? - Aqui.
Your name is Zheng Xiaoyu?
Yes.
ID?
- You're from Hubei? - I am.
Do you know anything about Shengli group?
I searched the Internet. I know a little.
This is Mrs. Jiao. She currently heads our company.
Why did you come so far to work here?
Do you have relatives here?
No.
A little older than the other suitors.
What kind of experience do you have?
I worked in a garment factory in Guangzhou.
Guangzhou! Why did you leave Guangzhou?
I wanted to feel fresh air.
Youre name is familiar. Are you running from some sort of problem?
Yes, I am.
In court, the judge changed his mind.
He dishonored me, called me a killer ...
I could not defend myself. I was forced to confess.
My tears fall.
Su san! Do you understand your sin?
Do you understand your sin?